ZARA KHAN

Web Developer & Designer

Dedicated Web Developer with 4+ years of comprehensive experience in visual Design, Typography, Responsive and Mobile Websites & Custom CMS designs. With Excellent skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Adobe Graphic Suite I am a passionate designer with creative thinking and project design abilities and provides strong attention to detail and design quality.

- Lahore, Pakistan
- ✓ ZaraMustafa@ymail.com
- in /TheZaraKhan
- zarakhan.netlify.app
- /TheZaraKhan

SKILLS & EXPERTIES

Soft Skills:

- Time management
- Communication Skills
- Critical Thinking
- Decision making
- Creativity Team Work

Hard Skills:

- HTML5
- CSS3
- Tailwind CSS
- BootstrapJavaScript
- jQuery
- WordPressWireframing
- October CMSReact JS
- Tools
- Adobe Graphic Suite
- Sketch Figma,
- Invision
- Git /Github
- Atlassian

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Dec 2018 - present

Web Developer and Designer at BlueLion Web Studio, Lahore, Pakistan

- ✓ Developed fully functional responsive prototypes based on Business Requirements using HTML/HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and jQuery.
- ✓ Determined the structure and design of web pages, and ensured that the web pages are responsive for multiple screens
- ✓ Developed features to enhance the user experience and Optimized web pages for maximum speed and scalability

Nov 2017 – Nov 2018

Web Developer and Designer at United Vision, Lahore, Pakistan

- ✓ Created the front-end design for a leading school management system that was successfully deployed in various schools in Lybia, Sudan, and Malaysia.
- ✓ Developed and maintained the company website
- ✓ Used best practices to optimize SEO

Feb 2017 – Oct 2017

Web Designer at Xgeeksters, Lahore, Pakistan

- ✓ Created web pages using standard HTML/CSS practices while incorporating data from back-end database and services.
- ✓ Used designing tools (Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator) to design and edit illustrations, vectors, and images to websites
- ✓ Build reusable code for future use

QUALIFICATION

2018 - 2020

MSCS - Masters in Computer Science

COMSATS University Islamabad, Pakistan

2013 - 2017

BSCS - Bachelors in Computer Science

Lahore College for Women University, Pakistan